<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title type="text" xml:lang="en">Leon Paternoster</title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com.com/feed/" rel="self"/>
    <link type="text" href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com" rel="alternate"/>
    <updated>2015-07-25T19:52:11+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://leonpaternoster.com</id>
    <author>
        <name>Leon Paternoster</name>
    </author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) Leon Paternoster</rights>
    
    <entry>
        <title>What we can learn from the Tories in opposition (and how there's an opportunity for the new Labour leader to remold the party)</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labour-leader-centre-opportunity/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labour-leader-centre-opportunity//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;OK, so I’m no analyst, academic, journalist, politician or philosopher and, if you’re interested, you will have heard or read 1001 opinions on who and what Labour should choose in the forthcoming leadership election. However, I am a Labour party member and I have thought hard about this. Here’s my twopenneth…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth looking at how the Tories fared in opposition. In 1997, they lost big – Labour won a 179(!) seat majority. The first post–Major leader was William Hague, who proceeded to lose big again, after which Ian Duncan Smith(!!) took the Tory helm. After that debacle the Tories selected Michael Howard – a relatively safe pair of hands – then finally settled on David Cameron after Howard lost the 2005 election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone once asked: what really went on there? And what can we learn from it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-leader-is-all-important&quot;&gt;1. The leader is all important&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that strikes me is I don’t remember a single Tory policy during the Blair and Brown years. Even Osborne and Cameron were quite happy to support Labour’s spending plans. I do, however, recall how shit Ian Duncan Smith was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;vid&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bXmQdi9pwDA?t=64&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe first leader after an election loss is a particularly difficult gig. However, Ed Miliband was a bad choice in the same way as Ian Duncan Smith, something the party sensed by backing his more rightwing but experienced brother. Like IDS Ed’s main battle was against his fundamental lack of credibility, which meant he spent most his time pulling the &lt;em&gt;good leader&lt;/em&gt; levers rather than expressing a &lt;em&gt;narrative&lt;/em&gt;. There were lots of good policies, but Ed always looked desperate and untrustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-government-holds-all-the-cards-opposition-is-about-opposing-well&quot;&gt;2. The government holds all the cards, opposition is about opposing well&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should remember Labour enjoyed a remarkably long honeymoon period, governing in a relative sea of calm. In 2001 their majority was reduced by a measly 12 seats. David Cameron became Tory leader post–Iraq, when the cracks were beginning to appear in the New Labour project. If he was a few years older his story would have probably been a lot different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opposition is just that. If the governing party appears to be doing a decent, competent job it’s unlikely the electorate will boot them out. All you can do is make life as difficult as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was absurd for Labour not to vote against the recent welfare bill, a complete failure in their duty to the country and the party. If it does have some sort of problem with appearing ‘soft on welfare’ who cares 5 years out from the next election? Unlike the 1997 Labour government, the Tories have a tiny majority of 12. They are vulnerable and should be attacked at every opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-not-the-policies&quot;&gt;3. It’s not the policies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you remember a single policy put forward by David Cameron in opposition? Themes, yes: the big society, hug a hoodie etc. All these told the story of a new, nicer Conservative party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will sound strange, but I’m sure it’s true. Policies in opposition are largely unimportant. Come election time that changes. Before then it’s mood, themes and, most of all, &lt;em&gt;narrative&lt;/em&gt;. All of which serve to make you more credible and electable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can drop the narrative once you’re in power. The big society was buried quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason Jeremy Corbyn appears to be so popular is that he doesn’t care how his policies play out in the electorate’s mind. He does, however, offer a simple, powerful story that resonates strongly with party members. Like Nigel Farage, you can believe he believes what he’s saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liz Kendall is &lt;em&gt;fairly&lt;/em&gt; clear about the Labour party’s purpose and problems; namely, that it’s shit and should give up on all that socialist stuff altogether. That’s easy to understand – the only problem is there wouldn’t be a Labour party left if she became leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What of Yvette Cooper and Andy Burnham? Could you name one thing they believe in? What’s their narrative?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is time and space to actually express an opinion about something rather than react to things. This isn’t a time for tactics but belief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;yvette-coopers-opportunity&quot;&gt;Yvette Cooper’s opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Labour party is dead on its knees, enervated by years of defensiveness and tortuous tactical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one good thing about opposition is that it gives you time to think things through, to establish a new narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yvette Cooper &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be a good leader. Although Corbyn has the best narrative he has an IDS credibility problem – the public won’t take him seriously as a leader. Liz Kendall is beginning to form a narrative, although she’s not particularly inspiring. More importantly, that narrative will destroy the party from the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the two ‘sane’ choices, Cooper ticks a lot of boxes. She’s talented, politically experienced and has lived in what politicians refer to as the real world. And, not to be too blunt, she is a woman. Electing a female leader would signal a clear change, and David Cameron has a woman problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;vid&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://embed.theguardian.com/embed/video/politics/video/2011/apr/27/david-cameron-calm-down-dear&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height=&quot;484&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be great if Cooper could establish a new narrative that appealed to the party. In my opinion, a traditional centre offering based around a theme of compassion would do well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would re–energise party members in these far right times, while providing a clear challenge to the Conservatives. Although policy detail isn’t important, a grand gesture wouldn’t go amiss. Something along the lines of scrapping tuition fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is she capable? Or has years of tactical obfuscation made it impossible? I fear the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How the Observer used dubious research and shoddy reporting to promote a Blairite Labour leader</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/observer-dubious-research-shoddy-journalism-blairite-labour-leader/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/observer-dubious-research-shoddy-journalism-blairite-labour-leader//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s Sunday, and &lt;cite&gt;the Observer&lt;/cite&gt; has published a slew of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/jul/19/corbyn-communist-labour-leader&quot;&gt;articles prediciting the death of the Labour party&lt;/a&gt; should we not learn the correct lessons of the 2015 election defeat. Those lessons are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;accept the Tory narrative on the economy to re-establish economic credibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/commentisfree/2015/jul/18/jeremy-corbyn-labour-leadership-election&quot;&gt;don’t vote for Jeremy Corbyn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m more than happy for &lt;cite&gt;the Observer&lt;/cite&gt; to have an opinion on the future of the Labour party. I don’t agree with the general &lt;em&gt;vote Liz or have a Tory government until 2030&lt;/em&gt; argument, but I do agree that voting for Corbyn would be a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the paper seems to have willingly taken part in a campaign to promote a Blairite leader, blurring the line between reporting and editorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facts are sacred and all that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lead story this morning was entitled &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/jul/18/labour-party-voters-desertion-election&quot;&gt;Labour’s lost voters may never return again, study finds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;, a hair raising report into focus group interviews conducted in 5 marginal seats won by the Tories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the less than convincing methodology and number crunching, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/profile/tobyhelm&quot;&gt;Toby Helm&lt;/a&gt;’s report failed to disclose information about the company that conducted the research that would probably have cast the surveys in a different light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple Google search reveals that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.campaignit.com/&quot;&gt;BBM&lt;/a&gt;, the company that conducted the focus group interviews, is a political and corporate campaigning company, not a research company&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.campaignit.com/bbm-people/&quot;&gt;BBM’s directors include Alan Barnard&lt;/a&gt;. Barnard was Tony Blair’s campaign and elections director.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have a pro-Blairite newspaper quoting a PR company headed by Tony Blair’s campaign director that produces research that backs the Blairite candidate for the Labour leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You smell a rat too?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/leonpaternoster/status/622700191066554368&quot;&gt;I tweeted Toby Helm&lt;/a&gt; to ask him why he’d failed to mention BBM’s political background, and who’d commissioned the research in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He hasn’t replied, so I’ll outline what seems obvious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some group to the right of the Labour party hired BBM to campaign for a Blairite Labour leader. &lt;cite&gt;The Observer&lt;/cite&gt; is taking part in this campaign by publishing editorial &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; misleading reports into research that has an obvious bias towards the Labour party’s right wing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shoddy journalism, all in all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How I became rich and used the benefits system to claim subsidies only for George Osborne to crackdown on me</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/how-i-got-rich-benefits-crackdown/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/how-i-got-rich-benefits-crackdown//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reader, I am rich. And, because I’ve been gaming the benefits system, &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.sky.com/story/1513430/crackdown-on-rich-council-house-tenants&quot;&gt;George Osborne is about to crackdown on me&lt;/a&gt;. Ask those marvelous Sky News journalists. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lbc.co.uk/crackdown-on-rich-council-house-tenants-112348&quot;&gt;And the ones at LBC&lt;/a&gt;. And the millions of other high quality websites fed news by Sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me, Bob Crow and Frank Dobson. Bastards all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, I live in social housing. When we moved in to this house I was the only person earning an income, and I earned less than I do now. I’ve moved on to a better paid job and my wife works, so we’re deemed rich, and will have to pay ‘market rates’ for my rent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By simply living here Sky reckons I’ve been ‘using the benefits system’. Because, no doubt, I am a benefits cheat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess some of you are thinking &lt;em&gt;Fair enough. Social housing is for people who need it. He can afford the private sector, so he should move out. There’s a deficit to pay off and we need every penny we can get&lt;/em&gt;, but if you bothered thinking it through for a few seconds more you’d maybe appreciate how absurd this idea is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should we move out of our family home and search for an overpriced, worse quality home in the private sector with a less secure tenancy because our income increased?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens if our income drops again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should any extra money we earn be offset by increasing our rent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is better quality, cheaper housing with a more secure tenancy the sole preserve of people on lower incomes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should social housing become some sort of ghetto for ‘poor’ people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is a ‘low’ rent a ‘subsidy’ when my landlord doesn’t receive more rent than I’m paying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What ‘benefits’ have I been receiving?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strip away all the ‘using the system’ bollocks, and is Osborne simply shaking me down for more rent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why aren’t you bothered by private landlords overcharging for crap, insecure housing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osborne’s devious logic is nothing new, of course, and neither is bovine acceptance. But what is interesting is the shift to middle earners. Apart from being utterly pointless, a £12bn saving will be &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; to find; he’ll need new folks to pickpocket. But he’ll have a battle on his hands this time, surely?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The vacant centre (part II)</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/zizek-far-left-moves-to-centre/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/zizek-far-left-moves-to-centre//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… if one looks closely at the proposals offered by Syriza, one cannot help noticing that they were once part of the standard moderate social democratic agenda (in Sweden of the 1960s, the programme of the government was much more radical). It is a sad sign of our times that today you have to belong to a “radical” left to advocate these same measures – a sign of dark times but also a chance for the left to occupy the space which, decades ago, was that of moderate centre left. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newstatesman.com/politics/2015/07/Slavoj-Zizek-greece-chance-europe-awaken&quot;&gt;Slavoj Žižek on Greece: This is a chance for Europe to awaken &lt;/a&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strange times, too – only recently, Labour moved so far to the right &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/the-last-liberal-centre-broke/&quot;&gt;the UK’s centre party became its most radical&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Žižek is ambivalent about this opportunity, but it is an opportunity nonetheless. If Labour or the Lib Dems won’t do it…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Labour's problems are only partly about how it talks</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labour-comms-purpose/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labour-comms-purpose//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://labourlist.org/2015/06/we-failed-to-defeat-the-tories-because-the-left-has-stopped-understanding-the-public/&quot;&gt;Sunny makes a good point about &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; leftwing communication&lt;/a&gt;, quoting Podemos’ Pablo Iglesias:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The enemy wants nothing more than to laugh at you. You can wear a T-shirt with the hammer and sickle. You can even carry a huge flag, and then go back home with your flag, all while the enemy laughs at you. Because the people, the workers, they prefer the enemy to you. They believe him. They understand him when he speaks. They don’t understand you. And maybe you are right! &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://labourlist.org/2015/06/we-failed-to-defeat-the-tories-because-the-left-has-stopped-understanding-the-public/&quot;&gt;We failed to defeat the Tories because the left has stopped understanding the public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he’s right. I’ve seen plenty of lefties really struggle to express their ideas without implying &lt;em&gt;but can’t you see it, you fool!&lt;/em&gt; - that’s if they manage to actually talk to anyone at all in 4 million ‘conversations’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s a danger we conflate the inability to express something in vaguely human terms with saying the wrong thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, just because the Tories have been able to construct a serviceable household budget metaphor as a justification for austerity, it doesn’t mean austerity’s right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunny reckons there are lots of &lt;q&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sunny_hundal/status/608561012455841793&quot;&gt;fiscally rightwing Labour voters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/q&gt; out there.  If we accept this (and I’m not sure where he gets his figures from) then it doesn’t mean they’re right either. Austerity could be (is) damaging for millions of people across class divides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem isn’t just &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; we make these arguments, it’s the fact that Labour doesn’t make them &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Labour can go down the Liz Kendall route and decide to accept the Tory version of austerity, and Labour’s own role in the financial crisis. That would at least be logical, and therefore more understandable than its attempt to offer austerity–lite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem with ceding ground to the Tories entirely is i) it’d inflict more damage on the UK and ii) Labour would lose touch with its constituency altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does austerity affect the majority of people in the UK, including those earning around average incomes? How does it affect household incomes? How does it affect house prices? The cost of things? Job security? These aren’t questions just for the left; start answering them and you can formulate a simple, understandable pitch to the electorate. Assume voters are inherently left &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; right wing and you’re doing them a disservice.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The last liberal and how the centre broke</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/the-last-liberal-centre-broke/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/the-last-liberal-centre-broke//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seems I spend my blogging life commenting on &lt;cite&gt;Guardian&lt;/cite&gt; articles about the Labour party and &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; election. Probably because I’m still traumatised by this image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;bleed&quot; src=&quot;/images/tory-poll.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2015 UK election exit poll forecast projected onto BBC centre. 316 seats to the Conservatives&quot; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption class=&quot;figcaption&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;If only it was 316&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some really useful, perceptive articles about what happened, what it means and what we need to do to stop 1000 years of Tory rule. I think I’ve come to the not particularly profound conclusion that Labour lost because voters didn’t feel the party could be trusted to run the country. It had little to do with policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons for this are a bit more complex, but trying to formulate a centrist approach to the economy while failing to challenge austerity and its narrative for 5 years resulted in a predictably confusing electoral pitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, today’s article is from Will Hutton. It’s about how Charles Kennedy wasn’t left of centre; rather, the centre, and Labour, had shifted rightwards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kennedy was routinely described in many obituaries as having taken his party to the left of New Labour. But such a description traduces the real political context. A refusal to be co-opted into an illegitimate, self-defeating war or later, in 2010, into a programme of crash public deficit reduction, almost entirely shouldered by expenditure cuts, should not define him as “left”. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/jun/07/tribute-charles-kennedy-revival-of-popular-liberalism-labour-lib-dem-policies&quot;&gt;A fitting tribute to Charles Kennedy would be a revival of popular liberalism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This explains why large swathes of Labour’s natural constituency fails to vote, or even supports other parties at election time, whether it’s the Lib Dems in 2010, or the Greens and SNP in 2015. It simply doesn’t stand up for its members’ interests; instead, it chooses to fight the Tories on their own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, politics as a whole has become a dance around right wing tenets like &lt;em&gt;the deficit must be tackled&lt;/em&gt;; so much so that Labour ends up pondering &lt;q&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/may/16/labour-great-crisis-ever&quot;&gt;modern social policy when there is no money around&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/q&gt; with a straight face. Ideas that would have seemed solidly central become radical. That prospective Labour leaders insist on dancing to this tune will only result in the collapse of the centre and more defeats. After all, there’s a real Tory party out there. At least what they say has some internal logic, even if it’s fundamentally wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/05/this-party-is-finished/&quot;&gt;A party that has lost its instincts is finished&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps the anti–Tory future lies in a rejuvenated liberal party firmly of the centre. I don’t believe the British are somehow naturally right wing, just as much as they’re not left wing. We need a party that can express simple ideas that question Tory assumptions about how economies work without tying itself in knots. Is Labour as a party capable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the phrase &lt;em&gt;the last liberal&lt;/em&gt; in my mind since Kennedy died. We’ve seen lots footage of him at anti–war rallies or on &lt;cite&gt;Have I got News for You&lt;/cite&gt; recently, but my strongest memory is of his first appearances on &lt;cite&gt;Question Time&lt;/cite&gt;. He really was impressive: humorous, clear, likeable; an alternative to pettyfogging politicians of all stripes and, most importantly, clearly &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; about a lot of things. Just what we need now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Labour's marketing politics</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labours-marketing-politics/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labours-marketing-politics//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mondeo Man&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;White Van Man&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;squeezed middle&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;aspirational working class&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;white working class&lt;/em&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;http://labourlist.org/2015/06/memo-to-the-new-leader-britains-real-middle/&quot;&gt;Labour’s search for a constituency continues apace&lt;/a&gt;. Just as long as it’s not the ‘something for nothing’ culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This marketing approach to politics, beloved of Blair, has surely had its day. Rather than simply define a set of problems that affect lots of people and then suggest ways we might solve them, Labour currently seems hell bent on finding an audience first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is symptomatic of a chronic lack of confidence; a fear or lack of any coherent identity, purpose or ideology. Until it figures out what it’s for rather than what segment of the population it needs to target, we’ll witness a gruesome parade of prospective leaders formulating more and more meaningless slogans – and then maybe select the most more–or–less–electable Labour leader.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A party which makes errors like this is already finished</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/this-party-is-finished/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/this-party-is-finished//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The newspaper reader says: this party will ruin itself if it makes errors like this. My higher politics says: a party which makes errors like this is already finished – it is no longer secure in its instincts. — Nietzsche &lt;cite&gt;Ecce Homo, Why I am so Wise §3&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Labour's constituency</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labours-constituency/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labours-constituency//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… in keeping with a technocratic mindset, you appear utterly oblivious to the notion of interest, that the organisations of public sector workers are the backbone of the movement that has provided you a seat in Parliament. You either forget or just don’t realise that the public sector is a constituency in and of itself, and it is supremely harmful to your own political interests to attack their wages and working conditions, to outsource them to third parties, to make their conditions of work less gratifying and less secure. Just go and take a look at the Conservatives across the chamber from you. Do you seriously think they won’t tackle zero hour contracts, abuses in the city, and executive pay because they have the wrong ideas? Or does it have something to do with the interests they represent? &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://averypublicsociologist.blogspot.co.uk/2015/05/dear-liz-kendall.html&quot;&gt;Dear Liz Kendall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked this article a lot, even though I’ve indulged in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/leonpaternoster/status/601447440831549441&quot;&gt;a spot of Liz baiting&lt;/a&gt; myself. If it looks and sounds like a Tory then to all intents and purposes it is a Tory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Labour’s constituency? Or was the 35% strategy simply an effort to rid itself of all constituencies and appease enough voters from everything else – the blob of normal – to form some sort of coalition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So perhaps it’s better to ask &lt;em&gt;what could Labour’s constituency be&lt;/em&gt;? Whose interests should it represent? Because it seems obvious that only the Greens are representing whole swathes of the population at the moment: public sector workers, workers who’ve been contracted out from the public sector, the disabled, students, union members, the unemployed, the part–employed, the precariously employed, the low paid, renters, people who can’t afford to stay on in education and their parents etc. etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you’re a home or asset owner, and in well paid, full–time employment you’re tripping over politicians purporting to represent you (I say &lt;em&gt;purporting&lt;/em&gt;; some argue &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/may/24/middle-class-living-standards&quot;&gt;the middle classes are having a tough time of it too&lt;/a&gt;). You’re a hardworking hero, the very backbone of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is not one of the prospective Labour leaders has moved beyond trying to appeal the same constituency. At the merest hint of anything left, they resort to the time honoured political past–time of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/andy-burnham-vows-tough-benefits-5786479&quot;&gt;getting tough on benefits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t an age of ‘one nation’ politics. Norman Mailer’s definition seems about right:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Politics is property… a delegate’s vote is his holding – he will give it up without return no more than a man will sign over his house entire to a worthy cause. &lt;cite&gt;Miami and the Siege of Chicago&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a vote – whose holding can Labour appeal to?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Labour</title>
        <link href="http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labour/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.leonpaternoster.com/labour//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But we cannot cling to the old dreams anymore,&lt;br /&gt;No we cannot cling to those dreams&lt;br /&gt;— &lt;cite&gt;The Smiths, Still Ill&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to publish a longish piece on the general election; why the Tories won, the wrongness of Ed Miliband as leader, trust, competence, shy Tories etc. etc., but you’ve probably read too many of these articles already. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/may/11/labour-missing-soul-burnham-umunna-cooper-disconnected-values&quot;&gt;A few of them are excellent&lt;/a&gt; – and what do I know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ed-stone.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Ed Miliband stands in front of an 8 foot 6 stone&quot; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption class=&quot;figcaption&quot;&gt;A better plan, obviously&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought I’d write something a bit more personal about the Labour Party, of which I’m a member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It strikes me Labour is first and foremost a party of contradictions. All parties are relatively broad churches with left and right, moderate and hardline wings. But the basic Tory &lt;i&gt;raison d’etre&lt;/i&gt; is a relatively simple sell: it’s the party (to paraphrase) of hard work, aspiration, reward, responsibility, low tax etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we define Labour’s purpose so easily? What’s it for beyond appeasing opposing views? It tries to ape Tory rhetoric while harking back to 1945 and beyond. Obviously, ideas such as aspiration and investing in education aren’t contradictory, it’s just that, in policy terms, Labour has been unwilling to reclaim them from a right wing interpretation. I’m not normally a huge fan of Owen Jones, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/may/12/tories-aspiration-labour-ambition-conservatives&quot;&gt;he absolutely nails it in this article&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, Labour has tried to have its cake and eat it by being &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/09/hate-labour-need-labour/&quot;&gt;neoliberal, but in a caring way&lt;/a&gt;. That’s bullshit on a grand scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has two effects. Firstly, it spawns a weird, evasive language I imagine the public finds baffling at best and alienating at worst – I know I do. &lt;em&gt;A better plan&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Controls on immigration&lt;/em&gt;. What controls? Why? Better than what other plan? Even in his resignation speech, Ed Miliband couldn’t rid himself of this double speak, and his goodbye email to the party was not from &lt;em&gt;ed@labour.org.uk&lt;/em&gt; but &lt;em&gt;onenationpolitics@labour.org.uk&lt;/em&gt; Again – &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;? What the fuck does &lt;em&gt;one nation politics&lt;/em&gt; actually mean beyond a clever clever play on an old Tory idea?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mug.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A red mug with the words Controls on Immigration printed on it&quot; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption class=&quot;figcaption&quot;&gt;That mug.&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.labour.org.uk/products/pledge-4-mug-controls-on-immigration-551/&quot;&gt;Incidentally, you can still buy a mug.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, us members are unenthused by the party’s policies. Why stay with Labour when it fails to offer a clear alternative to a damaging, decades old orthodoxy? The &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/09/minimum-wage-legalises-low-pay/&quot;&gt;occasional nod to a mildly non–neoliberal idea&lt;/a&gt; isn’t enough; nor is nostalgia for 1945 and not liking the Tories a lot. We’re a loyal bunch, but &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/09/hate-labour-need-labour/&quot;&gt;this passivity&lt;/a&gt; gets us precisely nowhere – as in 2010, prospective leaders will address us at hustings and apologise for fucking up so badly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you trust a party that can’t even appeal and talk to its own supporters?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been unable to move on from 1994, when triangulation and defensiveness were enough to secure comfortable political majorities. But things are different now: Scotland has gone and UKIP and the Greens offer distinct, albeit sometimes crazy and downright dangerous, alternatives to the status quo. And let’s not forget the new orthodoxy doesn’t allow for tax credit band aids or investing in new colleges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also the small matter of not even stopping the Tories. I’m sure they often feel the same way about their party, but at least they can cobble together a coalition or small majority. A dismal 35% strategy doesn’t cut it when you’re pulled in so many directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years of disciplined, centralised communications and policy making have stagnated the party. God knows what form new ideas will take – whether they’ll be more or less left wing – but what members don’t want to hear is Tristram or Peter going on about reconnecting with ‘aspirational’ voters as if it’s 1992 all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of us joined the party in 2010 because we really feared the Tories. We weren’t wrong. I’m sure many more will join this time round, but I’m worried we’ll just go down the same road of dutifully leafleting and supporting whatever more or less hapless leader we elect in the hope we can get rid of ‘them’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final thought on leaders – regardless of what we’re thinking and proposing, let’s choose one who’s half credible. And if they’re not up to scratch let’s not be afraid to ditch them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>