<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title type="text" xml:lang="en">No Bulbs from Leon Paternoster</title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nobulbs.com.com/feed/" rel="self"/>
    <link type="text" href="http://www.nobulbs.com" rel="alternate"/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <updated>2015-11-08T16:50:33+00:00</updated>
=======
    <updated>2015-11-04T09:06:19+00:00</updated>
>>>>>>> 2d8ff8c58e266190d2a86acfdd6992f6109b8436
    <id>http://leonpaternoster.com</id>
    <author>
        <name>Leon Paternoster</name>
    </author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) Leon Paternoster</rights>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Container housing &#8211; Right solution, wrong problem</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/container-housing-right-solution-wrong-problem/"/>
        <updated>2015-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/container-housing-right-solution-wrong-problem//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Impermanent, cheap housing isn’t new. Prefabs sprouted up around the country after the second world war, and some of them are still standing today, decades beyond their estimated 10 year lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/prefabs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prefabs in Ipswich&quot; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption class=&quot;figcaption&quot;&gt;A &amp;pound;160,000 prefab in Ipswich&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we’re living in austere times again, albeit self-inflicted. Whereas there may have been some logic in building prefabs after the war, there’s no reason not to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hbf.co.uk/media-centre/facts-statistics/&quot;&gt;build proper houses now&lt;/a&gt;, beyond inertia, nimbyism and ideology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2015 version of the prefab is a converted container. I imagine these may be an appropriate response to a very specific, short term need, such as ultra-cheap housing for homeless single people, or even students. I also suspect they appeal to urban designer types as they’re an inventive example of reuse. They’re also modular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure&quot;&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/containers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Converted container block&quot; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption class=&quot;figcaption&quot;&gt;Converted containers in Brighton&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet in Brighton, they’re merely &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/cities/2015/oct/09/living-steel-box-shipping-containers-future-housing&quot;&gt;adding to the stock of expensive rented accommodation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Brighton, on the English south coast, developer QED struck a five-year deal with the Brighton Housing Trust (BHT) to install 36 shipping container homes on a former scrap metal yard. The cost of preparing the site and converting the old units cost QED £900,000 – around £25,000 per container. The charity now rents them out to “tenancy-ready” people stuck in hostels or sofa surfing with friends. At £650, the monthly rent is not cheap, but it is 75% of the market rate in Brighton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Containers may seem a smart, inexpensive solution to a pressing problem, but that’s only the case when you’re failing miserably on so many other fronts: housing, for one, but also income, employment and the cost of living. And that’s all before you even tackle the question of  people living in metal boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Old Zizek</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/old-zizek/"/>
        <updated>2015-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/old-zizek//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Even in &lt;cite&gt;Living in the End Times&lt;/cite&gt; Zizek strikes a modest tone when it comes to the idea of revolution. The book begins at a very specific time, between times almost, just before the Berlin Wall is about to fall. He tries to harness this spirit, picturing a revolution free from Stalin &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;History grinds the left down. Here’s Zizek in fine, pessimistic form, looking for anywhere we can make a &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t see any historical guarantee that some big revolutionary event will happen. The only thing I’m certain of is that if nothing happens, we are slowly approaching — well, if not a global catastrophe, then a very sad society. Much more authoritarian, with new inner apartheids clearly divided into those who are in and those who are out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Okay, maybe I should have asked, where would this change come from, if it were to emerge?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a specific place. I see potential spaces of tensions. For example, you have literally hundreds of thousands, maybe millions of students in Europe who are doing their studies. And they’re well aware that they don’t even have a chance of getting a job. &amp;#8212;&amp;thinsp;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/2015/10/11/slavoj_zizek_on_obama_bernie_sex_and_democracy_thats_the_reality_of_global_capitalism_everyone_is_violating_the_rules/&quot;&gt;Slavoj Zizek on Obama, Bernie, sex and democracy: &amp;#8220;That’s the reality of global capitalism. Everyone is violating the rules.&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re leftwing, over the age of 40 and maintain any relationship with reality, pessimism is a natural state. Not necessarily, like Zizek, at human nature itself; more at the possibility of being able to affect any change. As the decades pass you realise there’s nothing inevitable about anything, least of all the fall of capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nietzsche’s objection to Marx was that he had a Christian, teleological view of the world. When you lose sight of paradise conservatism creeps in. Note Zizek’s views on Europe and immigration.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Haven't found it yet</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/not-found-it-yet/"/>
        <updated>2015-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/not-found-it-yet//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So much to read into that May defeat. Yet no-one seems willing to &lt;q&gt;learn the hard lessons and make some tough decisions&lt;/q&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, the left. We all know Ian Nosferatu Smith is evil, Gideon wants to get rid of the state and the Tory party will &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; reveal itself as the nasty party in the end. What we haven’t realised yet is that these aren’t reasons in and of themselves for enough people to vote Labour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last five years have been beyond anything else an exercise in finding out just how far up the economic ladder you can fuck over before you start losing votes. And the answer is &lt;em&gt;pretty fucking far&lt;/em&gt;. The lesson is quite simple: you can’t appeal to people’s better natures in order to get votes, you have to appeal to their fears and pockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Tories have appeared vaguely competent and dolled out a few bribes and promises of home ownership, the Labour left has waved its flags and gone on big marches. The morally right thing to do, but of limited use. Only once &lt;a href=&quot;/strange-popularity-of-george-osborne/&quot;&gt;the supposedly Machiavellian Gideon&lt;/a&gt; had the smart of idea of making 3 million voters hundreds of pounds worse off have the Tories looked vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Sunny said, &lt;a href=&quot;/labour-comms-purpose/&quot;&gt;the left has no idea of how to talk to people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But worse, far worse, is moderate Labour. As least the left is actually right about things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Cruddas, Danczuk et al have singularly, blockheadedly refused to learn is that the vast majority of Labour party members are sick of trying to appease austerity and xenophobia. This despite the fact that Jeremy Corbyn (yes, Jeremy Bloody Corbyn) got twice as many &lt;em&gt;party member&lt;/em&gt; votes in the leadership election than any other candidate, and was a single percentage point from getting an overall majority. Forget the three quiders; these are paid up, card carrying members telling the leadership that your job is to oppose austerity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of looking at how it might be possible to convert their members’ interests into votes, they simply try and interpret the current consensus, &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; trying to change anything outside the party. You wonder how far right this consensus would have to swing before they actually came up with a counterargument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/oct/25/corbyn-leadership-challenge-labour-mp-threatens-to-stand-if-may-elections-disappoint&quot;&gt;Danczuk apparently really believes he will get members to vote for someone like Chuka or Dan&lt;/a&gt; simply because they seem more reasonable than mad old Jeremy Corbyn. Meanwhile, Cruddas, another tactical mastermind, forms &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/oct/24/jon-cruddas-osborne-appears-more-in-tune-with-north-of-england-than-labour&quot;&gt;a pro-austerity group within Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How will this end? In some ways you feel the Tories will, true to form, merrily commit suicide over tax credits or Europe. But there needs to be a cogent, credible opposition that can talk to people in terms they understand and trust. At the moment it’s hard to see where that’ll come from.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>New Old Labour Old New Danger</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/new-old-labour-danger/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/new-old-labour-danger//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m old enough to remember this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/images/new-labour-new-danger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Poster of Tony Blair with New Labour New Danger caption&quot; /&gt;

&lt;figcaption class=&quot;figcaption&quot;&gt;A pre-1997 Tory election poster&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got that wrong, the Tories. Not sure it’ll work with Corbyn, but would be sensible to quietly drop the leaving NATO staff…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Murder in the cathedral &#8211; on Labour's tragedy (more Hamlet, really)</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/murder-in-the-cathedral/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/murder-in-the-cathedral//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ll post something more cogent on Labour’s tragedy soon, but, as the players learn their fate and the clock hands approach 12, here are a few thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Andy Burnham’s problem was that nobody outside the “Westminster Bubble” uses the phrase “Westminster Bubble”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liz Kendall’s problem was that she ignored the constituency and mouthed stuff about learning hard lessons; true enough, but they were the wrong lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yvette Cooper’s problem was starting too slowly, too timidly; again, she hasn’t grasped the austerity nettle. But she is the best Middle England candidate, where she’ll be known simply as &lt;em&gt;Yvette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeremy Corbyn’s great accidental strength was simply being against austerity. As such, hundreds of thousands projected their &lt;em&gt;desires&lt;/em&gt; onto an old hippy. None of the other candidates, to borrow a horrible business term, were &lt;em&gt;agile&lt;/em&gt; enough to realise this and adapt their message (Hamlet’s decadent court, if you like).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only Corbyn occupied the real, traditional, social/liberal democratic centre. That means he wins, which must be incredibly frustrating for those who thought they were the centre candidate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 quid voters won’t win a general election.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeremy Corbyn – one of too many jesters – won’t win a general election.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ed Miliband (another jester) made a fatal error, but it just may save the Labour party because it will have to bury and overcome its recent history (your tragedy’s ghosts).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loyal and hardy footsoldiers were actually leafleting during the high tragedy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The best hope for Labour is that the whole tragedy (or farce) does indeed end in a  good old bloodbath. From the ashes rises a proper leader of the old centre, who slays Brown Blairite ghosts and the hippy king. Your Fortinbras.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Show me the Next &#8211; genius concept, needs better content</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/show-me-the-next/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/show-me-the-next//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://showmethenext.com/&quot;&gt;Show me the Next&lt;/a&gt; is an incredibly simple app (or rather, an incredibly simple website). You visit, it displays an article and you press a button and it displays another article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://showmethenext.com/wp-content/themes/smtn/style.css&quot;&gt;next to no styling&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;/why-my-site-is-so-simple/&quot;&gt;even less than this website’s&lt;/a&gt; – and no navigation or archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admit to liking this idea (it reminds me of &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://guardian.gyford.com/&quot;&gt;Today’s Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;), although I’m not so sure there’s really ever a time when you just want something, anything to read without exercising &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; choice. &lt;cite&gt;Nieman Journalism Lab&lt;/cite&gt; reckons there might be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You’re on a long escalator with a phone in hand, and you want to thumb through something interesting quickly, without having to look for it. You’re sitting in gridlock traffic and tired of radio. You don’t want to skim Twitter or Facebook — you only want one story at a time, you don’t want to have to search for anything, but you still want to be surprised. &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niemanlab.org/2015/09/show-me-the-next-strips-down-online-reading-and-discovery-to-their-most-basic-components/&quot;&gt;Show Me The Next strips down online reading and discovery to their most basic components&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that’s right, but you’d need to be an expert curator and have a pool of top quality writing to draw from. At the moment the articles are a little too random, with a lot of stuff from Wikipedia. I don’t think it’s compelling enough when you can dive into McSweeney’s or Longform or your RSS feed with a just a tad more effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, there’s potential in the idea, or at least the process and technology behind it. And that’s what I really like about &lt;cite&gt;Show me the Next&lt;/cite&gt;. Pretty much anyone can build a barebones WordPress theme and link it to, say, a Pocket account. No overheads, no maintenance, no app and, most importantly, no actual writing. It works everywhere. Just me, my site and my Pocket button. There’s some real &lt;em&gt;chutzpah&lt;/em&gt; in that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And users don’t have to learn or think about anything at all. That’s always an interesting idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What content could work? Fiction? In depth, insider articles on, say, economics? I could get it built in a couple of hours…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Why my website looks so plain</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/why-my-site-is-so-simple/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/why-my-site-is-so-simple//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It does, doesn’t it? There are no decorative background images, no background gradients (or background colours, for that matter) and no animations. In fact, it barely looks styled at all (slightly misleading that: there are 14 files in my sass folder).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason’s quite simple. You don’t need any of that stuff to read articles on my blog. I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; put some effort into the things that make words easy or difficult to read on a screen. Body text is &lt;code&gt;23 pixels&lt;/code&gt; with a &lt;code&gt;32 pixel&lt;/code&gt; line height on a wide screen. The text is coloured &lt;code&gt;333&lt;/code&gt; rather than, say, &lt;code&gt;555&lt;/code&gt; on a white background. Lines won’t extend beyond &lt;code&gt;644 pixels&lt;/code&gt;. There’s a half line between paragraphs rather than a full line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I was using a different typeface from Freight Text Pro and these articles were 5,000 words long those numbers would be different so you could read just as easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m &lt;em&gt;constantly&lt;/em&gt; tweaking these settings. And because I’m always thinking about leading, measure, hierarchy and weight I get good at them. Not that you’d notice. The only thing you’d notice is a huge background image of a Macbook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that when you come to my site readability is the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; thing that matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do need to think about background images, gradients, animations etc. when you’re looking to employ me. Things get tricky then, because you’ll be wondering whether I can do all those things that make your website &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; right; when you’re looking at your own website not in terms of how well it works, but how it will impress your boss, peers and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ll get lucky and you’ll like a minimalist look. A lot of people do. Or maybe I’ll change things around a bit. Or maybe you’ll get into these articles and start using this site rather than glancing at it. Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Ambiguity</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/ambiguity/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/ambiguity//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… language in general actually tends to the simplistic, offering a reductive account of what it seeks to represent – it could hardly be otherwise. Hence we prize someone who has managed to put into language, with its relentless and crude semantic segmentation of experience, some of the density and indeed perplexity we feel as we try to get a grip on what is going on around us. — Tim Parks &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nybooks.com/blogs/nyrblog/2015/sep/01/clearing-up-ambiguity/&quot;&gt;Clearing up ambiguity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really liked this as it explains what makes writing &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;. Writing that makes you skip back through the text and reassemble the words and their meaning; not becuase the sentence has been phrased clumsily, but because it offers several interpretations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wading through too much non–ambiguous writing recently, mostly horror. There’s a lot of existential ambiguity in Lovecraft, but the prose is tortuous rather than nuanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure where that leaves didactic writers who are masters of ambiguity. Perhaps that’s Tolstoy’s strength?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Liz Kendall, an apology (and an appreciation of some of her ideas)</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/liz-kendall-apology-and-appreciation/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/liz-kendall-apology-and-appreciation//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I (we) owe Liz Kendall an apology. Firstly, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/aug/15/liz-kendall-labour-supporters-should-be-called-out-over-vitriolic-online-abuse&quot;&gt;she’s right to call out some party members on the tone of their criticism of her&lt;/a&gt;; it’s downright unpleasant, often sexist, and jars with Jeremy Corbyn’s &lt;em&gt;we don’t do personal&lt;/em&gt; message. It really is very fucking personal, and a gruesome glimpse into a certain left psyche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m not entirely unguilty, and was quick to join in with the &lt;a href=&quot;/labours-constituency/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;she’s a Tory&lt;/em&gt; name calling&lt;/a&gt;. Liz Kendall is not a Tory. Unfortunately, she made a catastrophic tactical error by setting herself against the traditional Labour party membership so staunchly from the outset – ironic, considering her radical ideas on devolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re the people who’ll vote (or probably not vote) for her, and the centralised, Blairite command and control approach hasn’t won an election for a decade. Who are the party leaders to tell us where we’ve gone wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, and more importantly, we’ve missed out on some interesting policy ideas. One criticism you could make of Corbyn is that there’s not much devolution in his world view; in that sense it represents &lt;a href=&quot;http://stumblingandmumbling.typepad.com/stumbling_and_mumbling/2015/07/on-corbynomics.html&quot;&gt;a continuation of centralised managerialism, just with a different set of bosses&lt;/a&gt;. And Kendall is, I think, quite interesting here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;leading-labour&quot;&gt;Leading Labour&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve published &lt;a href=&quot;/liz-kendall&quot;&gt;Kendall’s &lt;cite&gt;Leading Labour&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt; statement. Here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-idea-is-devolution&quot;&gt;The big idea is devolution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I like this. A lot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work for a divested mutual and we provide Suffolk a better library service than when we were a part of the County Council. We can make what we think are sensible decisions and act on them quickly (most of the time – the council signed a 5 year contract with our library management system provider back in 2012, so we’re stuck with that until 2017. We won’t be signing 5 year contracts for antiquated software in the future.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re a lot better than a Serco or Capita. And because we make smarter decisions outside of some insane, bureacratic framework, we save money too. Unlike Suffolk County Council, we also pay the living wage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The left really should welcome the idea of smaller, devolved, mutuals, and Kendall does differentiate this from risible big society ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Tories claim they want to devolve power throughout Britain. Yet they fail to match new responsibilities for councils with the resources and fair funding councils require. And the Treasury still controls everything including insisting combined authorities have elected mayors, whether local people want them or not. But Labour has been too timid on devolution in the past, and too slow to seize this agenda for our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As leader I will champion a new, comprehensive, nationwide model of devolution within the nations of the United Kingdom, including England. That means working with our cities, towns and counties to help them take on more power and responsibility over welfare, housing, health, education, transport and economic growth. Under my leadership, local authorities will be equal partners with ministers agreeing a new settlement for devolved powers and responsibilities every Treasury budget cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To tackle the real inequalities of wealth, opportunity and power that we face, Britain must undergo a radical and vast devolution of where power and decision making lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a socialist it must be hard to disagree with a devolved, mutual view of the world, no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slayed-by-the-ghost-of-the-austerians&quot;&gt;Slayed by the Ghost of the Austerians&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, events have completely overtaken Kendall (and Cooper and Burnham). Corbyn has grasped the austerity nettle which means – incredibly – he’ll win the leadership contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/jun/10/labours-liz-kendall-i-have-no-problem-aiming-for-budget-surplus&quot;&gt;silly, tactical noises to the electorate as a whole about ‘tackling the deficit’&lt;/a&gt; straight after an election defeat was a catastrophic mistake. All the leadership contenders should have addressed (no, &lt;em&gt;courted&lt;/em&gt;) the party and its natural constituency of public sector workers, the low paid, the unemployed, students, academics and liberals. Like I say, we’re the people choosing the leader, not the couldn’t-care-less voters of Ipswich, Lowestoft and Clacton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not stupid. We don’t &lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; Osborne when he talks about managing the economy well. We know how harmful he is. We &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to at least &lt;em&gt;discuss&lt;/em&gt; an alternative beyond &lt;em&gt;we can’t do anything until we get into power and this is the only way to win elections&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kendall notes &lt;q&gt;[The Tories] fail to match new responsibilities for councils with the resources and fair funding councils require&lt;/q&gt;, which is of course right. Although we’re more efficient than the previous library regime, we won’t be able to invest in, or maintain, the service if the Council continues to cut our funding every single year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But devolution in and of itself won’t cure that problem; tackling low productivity, lack of investment and underemployment will. Being a deficit fetishist will just make things worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame Kendall has sold herself as the Blairite candidate. Blairism is dead. It’s unforgivable, but perhaps unsurprising considering the years they’ve spent at the top of the party, that Yvette Cooper and Andy Burnham were unable to formulate any new vision or narrative for the party to get behind. Kendall is fresher, and does have some interesting, radical ideas. Perhaps her time will come again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, for better or worse, it looks like we’re going to get Jeremy Corbyn. God knows how that will end.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Occupy the centre, comrades</title>
        <link href="http://www.nobulbs.com/occupy-deserted-centre-pragmatism/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://www.nobulbs.com/occupy-deserted-centre-pragmatism//</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/may/09/tony-blair-labour-return-centre-ground-general-election-defeat&quot;&gt;British elections are won from the centre&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where is the centre? As in all things philosophical, the centre is a relative concept. It needs two poles to place itself between, namely the left and the right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, elections aren’t only won from the centre. What Blair meant was: elections are won by pragmatists who understand credibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s right, of course, but Blairite and Cleggian pragmatism also helped shift the centre towards the right. Not everyone likes that. It puts things out of kilter. You don’t have to be a Trot to think it leads to some downright &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2523819/Plan-cap-benefit-children-New-mothers-children-lose-700-5bn-welfare-crackdown.html&quot;&gt;unpleasant consequences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movement you represent can only take so much of it. Hence the Jeremy Corbyn phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zizek notes this is an opportunity for what’s nostalgically termed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newstatesman.com/politics/2015/07/Slavoj-Zizek-greece-chance-europe-awaken&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;hard left&lt;/i&gt; to occupy the old centre ground&lt;/a&gt;. And Corbyn is leading a merry dance into this &lt;a href=&quot;/the-last-liberal-centre-broke&quot;&gt;deserted liberal democrat land&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2015/jul/26/jeremy-corbyn-team-shocked-momentum&quot;&gt;See how happy this makes the troops&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But beware: credibility and authenticity are not the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His opponents are panicking because they have absolutely no idea of how to respond – apart from moving deeper into the pragmatic right while mumbling &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/jul/25/liz-kendall-labour-can-win-power-and-keep-principles&quot;&gt;a few compassionate words&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By definition mass electorates like things that come from the centre. Even the social democratic left, having shifted to the old centre right, could relearn this lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is: can the centre be redefined? Or has it been destroyed? Is it merely rhetorical? That’s what a new Labour leader should explore.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>
